Matthew Rose

1625 W Elizabeth St H6 Fort Collins CO 80521 - (970) 430-6717 - matt@composition9.com

Summary of Qualifications

Highly motivated professional with record of successfully developing, building and managing browser-based information systems. Seven years experience developing server-side scripted information systems, four of those years building Ruby on Rails applications. Experience in e-commerce, integrating with mobile development, inventory and project information management. Advanced degree in Management Information Systems. Strong background developing information systems while communicating technical information to non-technical users.

Major strengths include developing clean, behavior-driven code with heavy test coverage. Develops in an iterative, incremental fashion with strong agile tendencies to reduce scope creep and ensure the project is on schedule with the behavior requirements of the client/owner through to completion.

Professional Experience and Accomplishments

Designed, developed, tested, implemented, trained and maintained Ruby on Rails/MySQL project information management system for office and warehouse staff at 200+ employee general contractor. Conducted series of group and individual training sessions to familiarize users with functionality of system.

Developed, tested, implemented and maintained RoR/MySQL inventory management system and online e-commerce solution for custom furniture company, including custom cart and custom integration with Intuit merchant and accounting APIs. Set up system for parts suppliers to monitor inventory levels and send parts shipments when necessary.

Iteratively developed and continue to develop a contractor project management system to manage multiple clients and users, including project and ticket management, time-tracking and invoice management functionality.

Technical Skills

Ruby on Rails, REST, AJAX, MySQL, BDD (Rspec, Cucumber), Git, Subversion, XHTML, PHP, CSS, JavaScript, Linux, Apache, Passenger (Mod Rails), Merchant services

Education

Kellstadt Graduate School of Business - Chicago, Illinois

Relevant coursework included the following:

Information Systems Project Management

Operations Management

Management of Information Technology

Data Analysis/Statistical Software

Client & Server Application Development

Knowledge Management

Information Technology Policy/Strategy

Information Systems Analysis & Design

Behavior in Organizations

Programming in Java

Database Technologies

Electronic Business

Business & Ethical Environment

Voice/Data Networks

University of Illinois – Champaign/Urbana, Illinois

Bachelor of Arts with Major in Economics 2000

Relevant coursework included the following:

Economics of Technology

Economics of Natural Resources

Micro/Macroeconomics theory

Tax Rules and Regulations

Accounting & Accountancy

Economic Statistics

Professional Work History

Composition 9 Design, LLC - Fort Collins, Colorado

Sole Proprietor, Systems Developer 2005 – Present

Bulley & Andrews, LLC - Chicago, Illinois

Systems Developer/Accountant 2000 – 2005

Strawberry Fields Natural Foods Market – Urbana, Illinois

Assistant Grocery Manager 1999 - 2000

D & D Sealing and Services – Naperville, Illinois

Sole Proprietor 1995 – 2000 Summers